Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
دعم الإدارة، شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
[The Vendetta of An]
[ثأر آن]
Little one.
صغيري.
You've got quite the appetite.
لديك شهية كبيرة.
Here.
هنا.
Have something sour to cut the grease.
تناول شيئًا حامضًا لتخفيف الدسم.
Thank you, Mr. Yang.
شكراً لك يا سيد يانغ.
I'm full.
أنا شبعان.
Good.
جيد.
Settle the bill.
سدد الفاتورة.
Your father and I were like brothers.
كنت أنا ووالدك كالأخوين.
No need to pay.
لا داعي للدفع.
Father is father. I am me.
الأب هو الأب. أنا أنا.
I don't like owing anyone anything.
لا أحب أن أكون مديناً لأحد بأي شيء.
I'm leaving, Mr. Yang.
سأغادر يا سيد يانغ.
No.
لا.
Take all of it.
خذ كل شيء.
This boy.
هذا الصبي.
Who knows what he'll be like when he grows up.
من يدري كيف سيكون حاله عندما يكبر.
[Episode 17]
[الحلقة 17]
Sir.
سيد.
Take care.
يعتني.
[All-Goods Shop]
[متجر جميع السلع]
The pageboy hid himself in the Cangshui River.
اختبأ الصبي في نهر كانغشوي.
Is he fine?
هل هو بخير؟
Fine?
بخير؟
He was howling nonstop.
كان يعوي بلا توقف.
To keep me from getting out,
لمنعي من الخروج،
he nearly chewed through the skiff.
كاد أن يمزق القارب الصغير.
Speaking of which,
وبالحديث عن ذلك،
something this important,
شيء بهذه الأهمية،
you really plan to entrust him with it?
هل تنوي حقاً أن تعهد إليه بذلك؟
He's the only one who can pull it off.
هو الوحيد القادر على إنجاز ذلك.
He's not Huben.
إنه ليس هوبن.
He's someone who admires your junior sister.
إنه شخص معجب بأختك الصغرى.
I've seen him.
لقد رأيته.
He's a servant by Yang Chuhao's side.
إنه خادم بجانب يانغ تشوهاو.
What did you just say?
ماذا قلت للتو؟
He admires Xiaoqing?
انه معجب شياو تشينغ؟
With that kind of energy,
بهذا النوع من الطاقة،
he'd be better off getting his eyes checked.
من الأفضل له أن يفحص عينيه.
Xiaoqing is a good girl.
شياو تشينغ فتاة طيبة.
Don't talk too much.
لا تتحدث كثيراً.
Xiaoqing has never been good at music, chess, calligraphy, or painting.
لم تكن شياو تشينغ بارعة قط في الموسيقى أو الشطرنج أو الخط أو الرسم.
But she is a little glutton.
لكنها شرهة بعض الشيء.
So you should cater to what she likes.
لذا عليك أن تلبي ما تحبه.
Then may I ask, sir,
إذن، هل لي أن أسأل يا سيدي؟
what she likes to eat
ما تحب أن تأكله
and drink?
وماذا تشرب؟
Could you give me some guidance?
هل يمكنك أن تقدم لي بعض التوجيهات؟
I'm not sure about that.
لست متأكداً من ذلك.
But girls
لكن الفتيات
tend to like a bit of something sweet.
أميل إلى حب شيء حلو.
Thank you, sir.
شكراً لك سيدي.
You blockhead.
يا غبي.
Thanks.
شكرًا.
[Wontons]
[وانتون]
You are here.
أنت هنا.
Have a seat first.
تفضل بالجلوس أولاً.
- All right. - I'll get you a bowl of wontons.
- حسناً. - سأحضر لك طبقاً من الوانتون.
Here.
هنا.
Good.
جيد.
Boss.
رئيس.
For
ل
the past half month, you've been wearing that gloomy face.
طوال النصف شهر الماضي، كنت ترتدي ذلك الوجه الكئيب.
Is it that obvious?
هل الأمر بهذه البساطة؟
Of course.
بالطبع.
Boss.
رئيس.
Su came looking for me on purpose.
جاءت سو تبحث عني عن قصد.
He said,
قال:
you and I are old acquaintances,
أنا وأنت نعرف بعضنا منذ زمن طويل.
so he asked if I had any way
فسألني إن كان لدي أي وسيلة
to ease your worries.
لتخفيف مخاوفك.
That boy.
ذلك الفتى.
Well,
حسنًا،
what advice did you,
ما هي النصيحة التي قدمتها؟
my old partner, give him?
شريكي السابق، أعطيه؟
None.
لا أحد.
I told him
أخبرته
the boss is not an ordinary man.
المدير ليس رجلاً عادياً.
What troubles the boss
ما الذي يزعج المدير؟
can only be solved by Heaven.
لا يمكن حلها إلا بالقدر.
Boss.
رئيس.
We've both
كلانا
lived several decades, one way or another.
عاشت عدة عقود، بطريقة أو بأخرى.
When it comes to matters truly hard to decide,
عندما يتعلق الأمر بأمور يصعب حسمها حقاً،
I think
أظن
this is the only way.
هذا هو السبيل الوحيد.
Sha
شرب
is also one of the Liu faction.
وهو أيضاً أحد أفراد فصيل ليو.
You've been the one sheltering him.
لقد كنت أنت من يحميه.
So in some way,
لذا بطريقة ما،
you are a man who remembers past ties.
أنت رجل يتذكر العلاقات الماضية.
A man of feeling.
رجل ذو مشاعر.
I do not wish for him to die.
لا أتمنى له الموت.
What happens next
ماذا سيحدث بعد ذلك؟
I must entrust to you, Mr. Yang.
يجب أن أعهد إليك بالأمر يا سيد يانغ.
At our age,
في سننا،
we don't have many friends left.
لم يتبق لدينا الكثير من الأصدقاء.
You must
يجب عليك أن
not let anything happen to you.
لا تدع أي شيء يحدث لك.
Heads,
رؤوس،
and I enjoy wealth and peace.
وأنا أتمتع بالثروة والسلام.
Tails,
ذيول،
and I repay my debts.
وأسدد ديوني.
Stop.
قف.
This city wall can't stop me,
لن يستطيع سور المدينة هذا إيقافي،
and it won't trap you either.
ولن يوقعك في فخ أيضاً.
Rest assured.
اطمئن، لا تشغل بالك.
Don't be afraid.
لا تخف.
I had been thinking
كنت أفكر
that after you woke up,
بعد استيقاظك،
I wouldn't know how to face you.
لا أعرف كيف سأواجهك.
You are the Emperor.
أنت الإمبراطور.
I am nothing more than a commoner.
أنا لست أكثر من شخص عادي.
Should I call you Wuyang
هل أناديكَ وويانغ؟
or call you Your Majesty?
أم أناديكم بجلالة الملك؟
I don't know.
لا أعرف.
But now it's settled.
لكن الأمر قد استقر الآن.
We're parting ways,
سنفترق،
and you're still not awake.
وما زلتَ نائماً.
But I still have other matters
لكن لا تزال لدي أمور أخرى.
and must leave Cangshui River for now.
ويجب أن أغادر نهر كانغشوي في الوقت الحالي.
From here on,
من الآن فصاعدًا،
Mr. Long will send people to look after you.
سيرسل السيد لونغ أشخاصاً لرعايتك.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
Wuyang.
ويانغ.
If I come back alive,
إذا عدت حياً،
I'll go on taking care of you.
سأستمر في الاعتناء بك.
If I die,
إذا متُّ،
it will count as a valiant death for the realm
سيُعتبر ذلك موتاً بطولياً للمملكة
and I won't have disgraced our Xiao clan.
ولن أكون قد جلبت العار لعائلة شياو.
I'm leaving.
سأغادر.
Wuyang,
ويانغ،
when you're not holding a blade,
عندما لا تحمل سكينًا،
you're actually easy to get along with.
أنت في الواقع شخص سهل التعامل معه.
Here.
هنا.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Where is he?
أين هو؟
Are you the lad from the salt shop?
هل أنت الشاب الذي كان يبيع الملح؟
Sir.
سيد.
I'll take it.
أنا أعتبر.
So you still know how to show your face.
إذن ما زلت تعرف كيف تظهر وجهك.
You've skipped work for days on end.
لقد تغيبت عن العمل لأيام متتالية.
Are you
أنت
planning to quit on me?
هل تخطط للتخلي عني؟
No, sir.
لا يا سيدي.
Something came up at home.
حدث أمر طارئ في المنزل.
You reek of medicine.
تفوح منك رائحة الأدوية.
What is it?
ما هذا؟
Is your family member gravely ill again?
هل يعاني أحد أفراد عائلتك من مرض خطير مرة أخرى؟
Do you have enough money for the medicine?
هل لديك ما يكفي من المال لشراء الدواء؟
If not,
وإلا،
I'll lend you some.
سأقرضك بعضاً منها.
It's not that.
ليس الأمر كذلك.
Forget it, go on in.
انسَ الأمر، ادخل.
Go inside.
ادخل إلى الداخل.
All right.
حسنًا.
Here.
هنا.
Have some tea.
تناول بعض الشاي.
Hold it.
انتظر.
Warm yourself up.
قم بتدفئة نفسك.
You really don't seem short on money.
لا يبدو أنك تعاني من ضائقة مالية.
Look at you.
انظر إليك.
A whole new outfit.
زي جديد كلياً.
New clothes.
ملابس جديدة.
All dressed up all of a sudden.
فجأةً أصبحوا في أبهى حلة.
You must have someone you fancy.
لا بد أن لديك شخصاً يعجبك.
That's not why.
ليس هذا هو السبب.
This time I'm here
هذه المرة أنا هنا
to bid you farewell.
لأودعكم.
I'm going to Chang'an.
سأذهب إلى تشانغآن.
Before I leave,
قبل أن أغادر،
I want to admit a wrong to you.
أريد أن أعترف لك بخطأ ارتكبته.
This clothing is for you.
هذا الزي مصمم خصيصاً لك.
I noticed your clothes were patched.
لاحظت أن ملابسك كانت مرقعة.
So I bought a new one for you.
لذلك اشتريت لك واحدة جديدة.
All this
كل هذا
for the salt
للملح
you always sneak off with?
مع من تتسلل دائماً؟
This fine clothing
هذه الملابس الأنيقة
will settle the debt.
سوف يتم تسوية الدين.
So you knew all along.
إذن كنت تعلم كل شيء طوال الوقت.
But this time,
لكن هذه المرة،
it isn't just because of that salt.
الأمر لا يقتصر على ذلك الملح فقط.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Because
لأن
I know you're Zhang Mo's father.
أعلم أنك والد تشانغ مو.
And because you knew I was the killer
ولأنك كنت تعلم أنني القاتل
yet never blamed me.
لكنهم لم يلوموني أبداً.
You even let me stay here,
بل إنك سمحت لي بالبقاء هنا،
letting me work to earn money.
دعوني أعمل لأكسب المال.
And when I dozed off being lazy,
وعندما غفوتُ بسبب الكسل،
you covered me with your coat.
لقد غطيتني بمعطفك.
You sewed the old family letters Zhang Mo wrote
لقد قمت بخياطة رسائل العائلة القديمة التي كتبها تشانغ مو
into that coat.
في ذلك المعطف.
When I patched it,
عندما قمتُ بتصحيحه،
I learned who you were.
لقد عرفت من أنت.
It's fate.
إنه القدر.
It's truly fate.
إنه القدر حقاً.
If you'd stabbed me a few times,
لو طعنتني عدة مرات،
I might have felt better.
ربما كنت سأشعر بتحسن.
But instead you kept taking care of me,
لكنك بدلاً من ذلك واصلتَ الاعتناء بي،
leaving me ashamed.
أشعر بالخجل.
I came to Cangshui River
وصلت إلى نهر كانغشوي
with hatred in my heart.
بقلبي مليء بالكراهية.
Before you came to my salt shop
قبل أن تأتي إلى متجر الملح الخاص بي
to work,
للعمل،
I had already
كنت قد فعلت ذلك بالفعل
watched you for many days.
راقبتك لأيام عديدة.
But I found...
لكنني وجدت...
I found
لقد وجدت
you're just a foolish lad.
أنت مجرد فتى أحمق.
Always complaining with your mouth,
دائماً ما تتذمر بلسانك،
yet in your heart
لكن في قلبك
always thinking of others.
دائماً ما يفكر في الآخرين.
Caring for the sick at home,
رعاية المرضى في المنزل،
hoping
على أمل
a lost friend
صديق مفقود
would show up again soon.
سيظهر مجدداً قريباً.
You...
أنت...
The less you seem like a bad person,
كلما قلّ ظهورك كشخص سيئ،
the harder it is for me to hate you.
كلما صعب عليّ أن أكرهك.
If only you had never learned who I was.
لو أنك لم تعرف من أنا.
You did not know,
لم تكن تعلم،
and I would not have exposed it.
ولم أكن لأكشف الأمر.
Day after day,
يوماً بعد يوم،
life could have just gone on like that.
كان من الممكن أن تستمر الحياة على هذا النحو.
Forget it.
انسى ذلك.
It felt as if
شعرتُ وكأنني
Zhang Mo
تشانغ مو
were still here by my side.
كانوا لا يزالون هنا بجانبي.
You can pour the salt back into the funnel,
يمكنك إعادة صب الملح في القمع،
but time cannot be turned back.
لكن لا يمكن إرجاع الزمن إلى الوراء.
I truly wanted to kill you.
كنت أرغب حقاً في قتلك.
But child,
لكن يا بني،
what use is it if I kill you?
ما الفائدة من قتلك؟
Zhang Mo will not come back to life.
لن يعود تشانغ مو إلى الحياة.
Zhang Mo
تشانغ مو
was ordinary to begin with.
كان عادياً في البداية.
In this world,
في هذا العالم،
nothing is ever that perfect.
لا شيء كامل إلى هذا الحد.
Listen well.
استمع جيداً.
If you can do something great to help restore the realm,
إذا كان بإمكانك فعل شيء عظيم للمساعدة في استعادة المملكة،
to support the state,
لدعم الدولة،
then Zhang Mo
ثم تشانغ مو
will not have died in vain.
لن يكون موتهم عبثاً.
Get up.
استيقظ.
Sir.
سيد.
I am sorry.
أنا آسف.
Get up.
استيقظ.
Remember.
يتذكر.
From this day on,
ابتداءً من هذا اليوم،
you must live an honest and upright life.
يجب أن تعيش حياة صادقة ومستقيمة.
All right.
حسنًا.
[Wei Hour]
[ساعة وي]
Then,
ثم،
I will say something unpleasant.
سأقول شيئاً غير سار.
The human heart,
قلب الإنسان،
always has its darkness.
دائماً ما يكون هناك جانب مظلم.
You have it.
لقد حصلت عليه.
I have it too.
أنا أيضاً أعاني منه.
But do not be afraid.
لكن لا تخف.
No matter how dark it becomes,
مهما اشتد الظلام،
just like this Cangshui River,
تمامًا مثل نهر كانغشوي هذا،
your heart must always
يجب أن يكون قلبك دائمًا
hold a single light.
يحمل ضوءًا واحدًا.
I understand.
أفهم.
All right.
حسنًا.
Go on.
هيا.
Take this.
خذ هذا.
Eat it on the road.
تناولها أثناء السفر.
Go on.
هيا.
You are going to Chang'an to do something important.
أنت ذاهب إلى تشانغآن للقيام بشيء مهم.
Do not delay it.
لا تؤجل ذلك.
Go.
يذهب.
I have seen you now.
لقد رأيتك الآن.
My heart is settled.
قلبي مطمئن.
We part here.
نفترق هنا.
Go.
يذهب.
(Watch on www.dramacool.club Support Admin)
(شاهد على www.dramacool.club دعم الإدارة)
Sir.
سيد.
[Zuifeng Tower]
[برج زويفنغ]
Mr. Yang.
السيد يانغ.
This street
هذا الشارع
has suddenly gone quiet.
ساد الصمت فجأة.
Have you thought it through?
هل فكرت في الأمر جيداً؟
What Yan Fengshan
ماذا عن يان فنغشان؟
plans to discuss with the Tiemo people
خطط للمناقشة مع شعب تيمو
is no small matter.
ليس هذا بالأمر الهين.
If you stir up trouble now,
إذا أثرت المشاكل الآن،
kidnap the Tiemo envoy,
اختطاف مبعوث تيمو،
and something unexpected happens,
ويحدث شيء غير متوقع،
it is not only Yan Fengshan who will come after you.
ليس يان فنغشان وحده من سيلاحقك.
Even Tiemo assassins
حتى قتلة تيمو
will travel all the way to Chang'an
سيسافرون حتى تشانغآن
to kill you.
لأقتلك.
What Yan Fengshan wants to discuss with the Tiemo people
ما الذي يرغب يان فنغشان في مناقشته مع شعب تيمو
is nothing more than persuading them to send troops
الأمر لا يعدو كونه إقناعهم بإرسال القوات
to attack the Baiwenhu Army.
لمهاجمة جيش بايوينهو.
He plans to trade away northern territory,
يخطط للتنازل عن الأراضي الشمالية،
right?
يمين؟
The north is Xiao Wuyang's fief.
الشمال هو إقطاعية شياو وويانغ.
It is difficult to conquer.
من الصعب التغلب عليه.
So why not give it
فلماذا لا نمنحه إياه؟
to the Tiemo people
إلى شعب تيمو
and let them burn it barren?
وندعهم يحرقونها حتى تصبح جرداء؟
This scheme of Yan Fengshan
هذا المخطط ليان فنغشان
is not hard to guess.
ليس من الصعب تخمين ذلك.
As for my plan,
أما بالنسبة لخطتي،
I only want the Tiemo envoy
أريد فقط مبعوث تيمو
to meet with me once
أن تلتقي بي مرة واحدة
before he meets Yan Fengshan.
قبل أن يلتقي يان فنغشان.
After that,
بعد ذلك،
he can return wholly unscathed
بإمكانه العودة سالماً تماماً
to Yan Fengshan's side.
إلى جانب يان فنغشان.
You want to negotiate with the Tiemo envoy?
هل تريد التفاوض مع مبعوث تيمو؟
Can you afford the price?
هل تستطيع تحمل السعر؟
Naturally I cannot.
بالطبع لا أستطيع.
But someone can.
لكن بإمكان أحدهم فعل ذلك.
Chen Zhiying of the Huben Army
تشن تشيينغ من جيش هوبين
welcomes you here, Mr. Wuyin.
أهلاً وسهلاً بك هنا، سيد وويين.
Sir.
سيد.
I recognize her.
أنا أتعرف عليها.
She is indeed from the Huben Army.
إنها بالفعل من جيش هوبن.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Judging by the hour,
بالنظر إلى الساعة،
I should be going as well.
ينبغي أن أذهب أنا أيضاً.
You?
أنت؟
Surprised?
هل أنت متفاجئ؟
A man who lays the plan
رجل يضع الخطة
must step forward himself,
يجب عليه أن يتقدم بنفسه،
or else
وإلا
who would follow him in?
من سيتبعه؟
But...
لكن...
But I heard
لكنني سمعت
that you do not know any martial arts.
أنك لا تعرف أي فنون قتالية.
I have a stubborn life.
أنا أعيش حياة عنيدة.
I am not meant to die yet.
ليس من المفترض أن أموت بعد.
This street is not the same as usual.
هذا الشارع ليس كالمعتاد.
Be extra cautious.
توخ الحذر الشديد.
On guard.
على أهبة الاستعداد.
It is fine.
لا بأس.
Genghui is here.
جينجوي هنا.
No petty villain can get close.
لا يمكن لأي شرير تافه أن يقترب.
Sir.
سيد.
All is well.
كل شيء على ما يرام.
Then I will send men
ثم سأرسل رجالاً
to deal with those ruffians.
للتعامل مع هؤلاء الأوغاد.
Do not send too many.
لا ترسل الكثير.
It is clearly a ploy to lure us away.
من الواضح أنها حيلة لإبعادنا.
You all.
أنتم جميعاً.
Yes.
نعم.
Mr. Wuyin is unharmed.
السيد وويين لم يصب بأذى.
Bring out two horses.
أحضر حصانين.
Sir.
سيد.
The carriage is broken.
العربة معطلة.
We should switch to horses.
ينبغي أن نتحول إلى الخيول.
Very well...
جيد جدا...
Let go of him.
اتركه وشأنه.
Let go of him now.
اتركه الآن.
If you do not want your master to die,
إذا كنت لا تريد أن يموت سيدك،
step aside.
تنحى.
Tell them to move aside.
اطلب منهم أن يبتعدوا.
Stand down.
تراجع.
Out of the way!
ابتعد عن الطريق!
You are indeed no ordinary slave.
أنت لست عبداً عادياً على الإطلاق.
As long as you cooperate, sir,
طالما أنك تتعاون يا سيدي،
I will not harm you in the slightest.
لن أؤذيك على الإطلاق.
Young man,
شاب،
which way is the exit?
أين المخرج؟
Are you Tiemo people?
هل أنتم من محبي تيمو؟
The meteor iron from the altar
الحديد النيزكي من المذبح
of Mount Shiluoman
جبل شيلومان
obtained through ritual,
تم الحصول عليها من خلال الطقوس،
is worn only by Tiemo nobles.
لا يرتديه إلا نبلاء تيمو.
Even if you changed into Han clothing,
حتى لو ارتديت ملابس هان،
the meteor iron on your chest
الحديد النيزكي على صدرك
is far too obvious.
الأمر واضح للغاية.
You know of Mount Shiluoman's altar.
أنت تعرف مذبح جبل شلومان.
Are you Tiemo people as well?
هل أنتم أيضاً من مستخدمي تيمو؟
Lately Tiemo people are not very welcome
في الآونة الأخيرة، لم يعد سكان تيمو موضع ترحيب كبير
on the streets of Chang'an.
في شوارع تشانغآن.
Explain as we walk.
اشرح لنا أثناء سيرنا.
Can you take me to Yankang Ward?
هل يمكنك أن تأخذني إلى حي يانكانغ؟
You will be well rewarded.
ستُكافأ مكافأةً مجزية.
There are too many patrols at night.
هناك عدد كبير جداً من الدوريات الليلية.
I dare not
لا أجرؤ
escort a Tiemo noble down the street.
مرافقة أحد نبلاء تيمو في الشارع.
Then take me in for the night.
ثم خذني معك لقضاء الليلة.
Send me there at dawn.
أرسلني إلى هناك عند الفجر.
Young man,
شاب،
just for one night.
لليلة واحدة فقط.
I will not treat you poorly.
لن أعاملك معاملة سيئة.
Chang'an is so vast.
مدينة تشانغآن شاسعة للغاية.
Why do you live in such a shabby alley?
لماذا تعيش في هذا الزقاق الرث؟
For Tiemo people in Chang'an,
بالنسبة لسكان تيمو في تشانغآن،
there are not many ways to make a living.
لا توجد طرق كثيرة لكسب العيش.
Usually,
عادة،
we sell a bit of leather goods,
نبيع بعض المنتجات الجلدية،
which barely keeps life going.
وهو ما يكفي بالكاد للحفاظ على استمرار الحياة.
Times are unsettled now,
الأوضاع مضطربة الآن،
so we moved here.
لذا انتقلنا إلى هنا.
We are almost there.
لقد اقتربنا من الوصول.
Come on.
تعال.
Heads means enjoying wealth and honor.
تعني كلمة "رؤوس" التمتع بالثروة والشرف.
Tails means paying off the debt.
يعني "الوجه" سداد الدين.
I am Yang Chuhao of the Huben Army.
أنا يانغ تشوهاو من جيش هوبين.
I greet you, Mr. Wuyin.
أحييك يا سيد وويين.
Do not fear, sir.
لا تخف يا سيدي.
You know me.
أنت تعرفني.
I know you are Yang Chuhao.
أعلم أنك يانغ تشوهاو.
But you cannot appear out of nowhere.
لكن لا يمكنك الظهور من العدم.
Anyone would be frightened.
أي شخص سيشعر بالخوف.
Who is he?
من هو؟
He is with the people who tried to seize you just now.
إنه مع الأشخاص الذين حاولوا القبض عليك الآن.
A linked scheme.
مخطط مترابط.
I almost fell for it.
كادت أن تنطلي عليّ الحيلة.
Sir,
سيد،
this place may not be safe.
قد لا يكون هذا المكان آمناً.
I should escort you away first,
ينبغي عليّ أن أرافقك بعيداً أولاً،
then send people to eliminate them.
ثم أرسلوا أشخاصاً للقضاء عليهم.
Good thing you arrived in time.
من حسن الحظ أنك وصلت في الوقت المناسب.
To protect you well,
لحمايتك جيداً،
I would give my life without hesitation.
سأضحي بحياتي دون تردد.
Sir, please.
سيدي، من فضلك.
Let us go.
هيا بنا.
What is this?
ما هذا؟
Did you bring a blade?
هل أحضرت سكينًا؟
No...
لا...
Yang Chuhao.
يانغ تشوهاو.
Come.
يأتي.
Help me quickly.
ساعدني بسرعة.
All right.
حسنًا.
So heavy.
ثقيل جداً.
[Warrant]
[مذكرة]
No.
لا.
All along the way you kept telling me to be cautious.
طوال الطريق كنت تنصحني بالحذر.
Chang'an truly is unsettled.
مدينة تشانغآن مضطربة حقاً.
Anyone who can set themselves against the Huben Army...
أي شخص يستطيع أن يقف في وجه جيش هوبن...
is him?
هل هو هو؟
It looks like...
يبدو أن...
Yes, it must be him.
نعم، لا بد أنه هو.
This man
هذا الرجل
has been wanted by the Huben Army for fifteen years.
مطلوب من قبل جيش هوبن منذ خمسة عشر عاماً.
Mr. Wuyin,
السيد وويين،
this time
هذه المرة
you have made great merit.
لقد حققتَ فضلاً عظيماً.
Genghui.
جينجوي.
Sir.
سيد.
This is...
هذا هو...
Say no more.
لا داعي للمزيد من الكلام.
Give me the blade.
أعطني النصل.
Since he is wanted by the Huben Army,
بما أنه مطلوب من قبل جيش هوبن،
I shall claim this merit first.
سأطالب بهذا الفضل أولاً.
Sir, wait.
سيدي، انتظر.
Sir,
سيد،
he is Liu Ziwen's son.
هو ابن ليو Ziwen.
He is remarkably gifted.
إنه موهوب بشكل ملحوظ.
To kill him would be a waste.
إن قتله سيكون مضيعة للوقت.
Alive, he is far more useful to us.
وهو على قيد الحياة، سيكون أكثر فائدة لنا بكثير.
General Fengshan still wants to see him.
لا يزال الجنرال فنغشان يرغب في رؤيته.
Yan Fengshan bears deep hatred for him,
يكنّ يان فنغشان له كراهية شديدة.
and has him wanted across the city.
وهو مطلوب في جميع أنحاء المدينة.
Then take it as my gift to Yan Fengshan.
إذن خذها كهدية مني إلى يان فنغشان.
Come.
يأتي.
Sir, you were frightened.
سيدي، لقد كنت خائفاً.
The carriage is here.
العربة هنا.
I promise
أعدك
that from now on
من الآن فصاعدًا
you will not be disturbed again.
لن يتم إزعاجك مرة أخرى.
Please, sir.
من فضلك سيدي.
Carry him away.
احمله بعيداً.
Yes.
نعم.
Was this also part of the plan?
هل كان هذا أيضاً جزءاً من الخطة؟
I do not know.
لا أعلم.
When you read this letter,
عندما تقرأ هذه الرسالة،
I will most likely have been captured.
على الأرجح سيتم أسري.
But do not worry.
لكن لا تقلق.
The plan is still under control.
الخطة لا تزال تحت السيطرة.
As for why I arranged this,
أما عن سبب قيامي بترتيب هذا،
first,
أولاً،
it is for my acquaintance Yang Chuhao.
هذا من أجل معارفي يانغ تشوهاو.
The old debt he owed has been repaid.
تم سداد الدين القديم الذي كان مديناً به.
He should not be implicated any further.
لا ينبغي توريطه في أي شيء آخر.
By using this plan,
باستخدام هذه الخطة،
I can win him
أستطيع أن أفوز به
some time to break away from Yan Fengshan.
بعض الوقت للابتعاد عن يان فنغشان.
Second,
ثانية،
it is because of Ye Zheng.
ذلك بفضل يي تشنغ.
Your martial skills are strong,
مهاراتك القتالية قوية،
but you lose your calm when you care.
لكنك تفقد هدوءك عندما تهتم.
If you knew the entire plan,
لو كنتَ تعرف الخطة بأكملها،
you would try to stop me.
كنت ستحاول منعي.
Third,
ثالث،
[Letter] when the Huben Army captures me,
[رسالة] عندما يقبض عليّ جيش هوبن،
the secret I carry
السر الذي أحمله
can draw Yan Fengshan's attention for a while.
يمكن أن يجذب انتباه يان فنغشان لبعض الوقت.
And that
وذلك
will be our best chance to negotiate
ستكون هذه أفضل فرصة لنا للتفاوض
with the Tiemo envoy.
مع مبعوث تيمو.
The one going to negotiate
الشخص الذي سيتفاوض
is already on the way.
هو في طريقه بالفعل.
This plan may be dangerous,
قد تكون هذه الخطة خطيرة،
[Spring Wind. The Yuan Bird arrives.]
[رياح الربيع. وصول طائر اليوان.]
[Thunder stirs. Lightning begins.] but it is exactly what I wished for.
[دوى الرعد. وبدأ البرق.] لكن هذا بالضبط ما كنت أتمناه.
To confront Yan Fengshan face to face is,
مواجهة يان فنغشان وجهاً لوجه هي،
in all my life,
طوال حياتي،
the meeting I have anticipated most.
الاجتماع الذي كنت أنتظره بفارغ الصبر.
♪The wind never rests♪
♪الريح لا تهدأ أبداً♪
♪How much pain does it scatter to nothing?♪
♪كم من الألم يتبدد حتى يختفي؟♪
♪The rain knows no calm♪
♪المطر لا يعرف الهدوء♪
♪How much love does it cool into silence?♪
♪كم من الحب يبرد حتى يصمت؟♪
♪All my life amid blades and shadows♪
♪ طوال حياتي وسط السيوف والظلال ♪
♪I live beside life and death♪
♪أعيش بين الحياة والموت♪
♪In a landscape veiled in smoke and fire♪
♪في منظر طبيعي يكتنفه الدخان والنار♪
♪I can only live under a hidden name♪
لا أستطيع العيش إلا تحت اسمٍ خفي.
♪Even my sighs must fall softly♪
♪حتى تنهداتي يجب أن تكون هادئة♪
♪The heart is unsteady♪
♪القلب غير مستقر♪
♪How much hatred does it leave unnamed?♪
♪كم من الكراهية تترك دون تسمية؟♪
♪The dream will not end♪
♪لن ينتهي الحلم♪
♪How many lives does it bind to fate?♪
♪كم من الأرواح يربطها القدر؟♪
♪Bearing my family's fate♪
♪أتحمل مصير عائلتي♪
♪I can only stand firm♪
♪لا يسعني إلا أن أبقى ثابتاً♪
♪I let my vows ring true♪
♪أجعل عهودي صادقة♪
♪So the common folk need not wander♪
♪حتى لا يضطر عامة الناس إلى التيه♪
♪I have faith in it♪
♪أنا أؤمن بذلك♪
♪So I choose♪
♪لذا أختار♪
♪To cut off the past, to part in life♪
♪لقطع الصلة بالماضي، وللانفصال عن الحياة♪
♪Across thousands of li♪
♪عبر آلاف الليالي♪
♪Who makes me vanish without a word?♪
♪من الذي يجعلني أختفي دون كلمة؟♪
♪I seek refuge deep in the mountains♪
♪أبحث عن ملجأ في أعماق الجبال♪
♪Playing a game that spans ten long years♪
♪لعب لعبة تمتد لعشر سنوات طويلة♪
♪At last I step out from every secret♪
♪أخيرًا أخرج من كل الأسرار♪
♪Standing opposed to both grace and grievance♪
♪الوقوف في وجه كل من النعمة والظلم♪
♪Without the slightest fear♪
♪بدون أدنى خوف♪
♪Along the ancient road, I spur my horse♪
♪على طول الطريق القديم، أحثّ حصاني♪
♪And ride away♪
♪ وانطلق بعيدًا ♪
♪So I choose to cut off the past♪
♪لذا اخترتُ أن أقطع علاقتي بالماضي♪
♪At sunset, beacon fires rise♪
♪عند غروب الشمس، ترتفع نيران المنارات♪
♪But I fear no bloodshed♪
♪لكنني لا أخشى إراقة الدماء♪
♪In the mortal world, I carry my pride♪
♪في عالم البشر، أحمل كبريائي♪
♪News reaches me from Chang'an♪
♪تصلني الأخبار من تشانغآن♪
♪Along the way, I endure disgrace and set my schemes♪
♪على طول الطريق، أتحمل العار وأضع خططي♪
♪My blade falls upon my foes♪
♪ سيفي يهوي على أعدائي ♪
♪Then I leave the jianghu behind♪
♪ثم أترك الجيانغو خلفي♪
♪Traveling to the ends of the earth♪
♪السفر إلى أقاصي الأرض♪
♪Disappearing into the wide world♪
♪الاختفاء في العالم الواسع♪